THANG NGUYEN

As an experienced IT Business Analyst, I have spent the last 4 years working with both product companies and outsourcing firms, honing my skills in project management, requirements gathering, and stakeholder communication. However, what truly sets me apart is my passion for UX/UI design and my strong background in software and data. I am constantly seeking new ways to enhance user experiences and streamline processes

Experiences

FPT Software, Da Nang

IT BUSINESS ANALYST

I improved my mindset and technical knowledge a lot when working at my present company. There were various challenges when working on outsourcing projects for client came from abroad. At last, I found myself really like this job and ready for new

- Gather requirements
- Communicate and validate requirements with stakeholders
- Write User Story, Use Cases, FSD, SRS
- Design Mock-up, Wireframe, Prototype
- Analyze data and writing query script
- Coordinate with different teams to ensure the quality of outcomes
- Plan and organize schedule to ensure launch on time along the project roadmap
- Support in testing, verifying bugs or issues with client

FAST Software, Da Nang

IT BUSINESS ANALYST

The first company I had joined immediately after graduation from university. I really appreciate for experiences given from this first job. I improved a lot of a BA's main skills through doing projects such as communicate with stakeholders, writing documents, working directedly with the system and so on.

- Gather requirements from stakeholders and write down feature list
- Communicate and validate requirements with stakeholders
- Write Business Requirement Document, Project Vision Document, User guide
- Senerios Testing
- $\bullet\,\,$ Onsite and analyze process issues to make improvements through digital transformation
- Coordinate with different teams to ensure the quality of outcomes
- Plan and organize

Advertising Agency, Da Nang

DESIGNER & COPY WRITER

The part time job when I was a student at university. I learned a huge knowledge about digital marketing through working with my team leader, my knowledge I was learned mainly focus on SEO. I also learned the organizing and planning skills, team working

- Working as Designer
- Edit marketing videos
- Conduct SEO campaign
- Write content for SEO campaign

What can I do?

Comfortable on team working effectively with **Agile** model. Using proficient technical tools for working such as Figma, Balsamiq for UX design. **Can read and understand programing language**. Experience in reading, analysing, developing diagrams UML, using BPMN on modeling business process. Planning and organizing my tasks, conduct **business requirements documents**. Furthermore, I have good communication ability to connect with colleagues.

Personal Info

- **#** 05-11-1996
- (+84) 0906.401.845
- thangnh0511@gmail.com
- O Da Nang, Viet Nam

Education

Bachelor of Management Information System (2015-2019) **Da Nang University of Economic, Viet Nam**

Certification

- PSPO 1 2023
- FPT BA Foundation- 2023
- TOEIC 2022
- Google UX Design Professional 2022
- Codegym JavaScript 2022
- Codegym HTML/CSS 2021
- MOS Excel 2013 Specialist 2017

Technical Skills

Management & Design Tools

- Jira & Confluence
- Balsamiq, Figma, Adobe XD
- Draw.io, MS Visio, Miro
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Business Process Model and Notation (BPMN)

Database

■ MS SQL Server, Oracle

Programing

- HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React
- Python

English Skill

Professional working proficiency **TOEIC - 765 Score**

HOBbies

- Running
- Playing guitar
- Reading books
- Traveling
- Coding
- Garden

I think there'is no problem that we cannot solve. Every challenge that I face today makes me stronger tomorrow. One of the things I'have always been confident about in myself is the ability to organize my time for work and update new knowledge about methods, tools, and technology.

Thank you for your reading,

2021 - CURRENT

Professional Experiences

Jan 2023 - Current

Company

FPT Software, Da Nang

Role

IT Business Analyst

Team size

14

Technologies Magento Flatform

Marketing Automation

Developing new modules and enhancing the e-commerce website.

Responsibilities

- Gathering and Planning requirements
- Writing document (SRS, Wireframe)
- Support UAT previous phase

Jun 2022 - Nov 2022

Company

FPT Software, Da Nang

Role

IT Business Analyst

Team size

20

Technologies

Oracle

Marketing Automation

Maintain and enhance the internal system of a bank designed for helping the marketing department rapidly run a new marketing campaign by refund for customers who use bank's service.

Responsibilities

- Receive requirements and closely working with project team of client side to clarify and write terms and conditions document
- Writing SQL queries statement based on terms and conditions document of the marketing campaign
- Scenarios testing for queried lists

Mar 2022 - may 2022

Company

FPT Software, Da Nang

Role

IT Business Analyst

Team size

18

Technologies MSSQL, React, .NET

Data Migration

Data migration by using SQL query statements to mapping data from old system to new system based on requirements

Responsibilities

- Create the mapping document base on using table definition, old system and SRS of new system
- Communicate with BA and Dev to clarify information about SRS and

feb 2022 - mar 2022

Company

FPT Software, Da Nang

Role

IT Business Analyst

Team size

8

Technologies

Azure, Power Platform, .NET, JavaScript

Customer Service Portal

Developing Customer Service Portal for insurance term designed for helps internal staff and third party staff promptly support customer

Responsibilities

- Gather requirements from client and PO
- Writing User Story, FSD, SRS
- Design Wireframe, Prototype
- Scenerios testing, support clarify issues and bugs with clients

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

Company

FPT Software, Da Nang

Role

IT Business Analyst

Team size 10

Technologies

Azure, MS D365, .NET,

JavaScript

Customer Relationship Management System

Maintain and enhancement Customer Relationship Management System.

Responsibilities

- Communicate with PO and client to clearly understand business process and provide solution to enhancement
- Writing User Story, FSD
- Design Wireframe, prototype for new screens
- Support scenerios testing, and clarify issues and bugs on launch phrase

jan 2021 - apr 2021

Company

Fast Software, Da Nang

Role

IT Business Analyst

Team size

4

Technologies MSSQL, .NET

Accounting Software

Digital transformation for business

Responsibilities

- Implementing the accounting and ERP system standard version and support client for using in person, also gather change request
- Communicate with stakeholders to clarify requirements and solution
- Write Business requirement documents

apr 2020 - mar 2021

Company

Fast Software, Da Nang

Role

IT Business Analyst

Team size

6

Technologies MSSQL, .NET

Purchasing Management System

ERP system designed for help warehouse and purchasing management

Responsibilities

- Onsite and communicate with stakeholders to gather requirements and clarify business issues
- Plan and organize roadmap of project
- Write business requirement document include current state analysis, business requirement solution
- Work closely with Dev and tester to keep tracking project ensure launch on time
- Scenrios test and write user guide

jan 2020 - mar 2020

Company

Fast Software, Da Nang

Role

IT Business Analyst

Team size

6

Technologies

MSSQL, .NET

Accounting Software

Connecting data from other system to accounting system that support to manage accounting, warehouse, and human resource for Da Nang port

Responsibilities

- Working onsite to research the operation of logistic process in port
- Writing current state analysis document and transfer to team
- Following and support client using system
- Working with developer to hotfix bugs

nov 2019 - Dec 2019

Company

Fast Software, Da Nang

Role

IT Business Analyst

Team size

7

Technologies MSSQL, .NET

Vehicle Weighing Station

Connecting data from manufactory system to vehicle weighing software

Responsibilities

- Observe and study operation to make business process model
- Discuss and Provide solution
- Support and fixing problems on database and business process
- Prepare user guide and make training session to user